const e=[{number:1,question:"Which of the following has been found to be helpful in reducing the risk of moderate to severe premenstrual symptoms?",options:{A:"Omega-3 fatty acids.",B:"Vitamin B12.",C:"Vitamin E.",D:"Calcium plus vitamin D.",E:"Flaxseed oil."},correct_answer:"D",explanation:""},{number:2,question:"Exposure to which of the following selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs) during gestation increases the risk of fetal cardiac abnormalities?",options:{A:"Fluoxetine.",B:"Paroxetine.",C:"Fluvoxamine.",D:"Sertraline.",E:"Clomipramine."},correct_answer:"B",explanation:""},{number:3,question:"Which of the following symptoms has been associated with third-trimester fetal exposure to selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs)?",options:{A:"Increased muscle tone.",B:"Hyperglycemia.",C:"Ketoacidosis.",D:"Seizures.",E:"Pulmonary hypotension."},correct_answer:"D",explanation:""},{number:4,question:"Which of the following statements about lithium treatment of bipolar disorder during pregnancy is true?",options:{A:"Lithium can be discontinued because pregnancy is protective against bipolar mood instability.",B:"After delivery, lithium should be restarted at the preconception dose as soon as the mother has been stabilized.",C:"A preeclamptic patient's lithium dose remains the same.",D:"Lithium should not be discontinued prior to giving birth.",E:"The patient's lithium concentration remains the same during pregnancy as it had been prior to pregnancy."},correct_answer:"B",explanation:""},{number:5,question:"Which of the following statements about postpartum psychosis is true?",options:{A:"In most cases, mothers with postpartum psychosis should not breast-feed.",B:"The incidence of postpartum psychosis is estimated at 1 in 10,000.",C:"Postpartum psychosis tends to be of late onset (usually by the second to third month after delivery).",D:"Postpartum psychosis seldom affects the mother's sleep.",E:"Most cases of postpartum psychosis are thought to be a manifestation of schizophrenia."},correct_answer:"A",explanation:""},{number:6,question:"Which of the following statements about the use of electroconvulsive therapy (ECT) during pregnancy is true?",options:{A:"Pelvic examination and uterine tocodynamometry to exclude uterine contractions are not essential prior to ECT.",B:"Elevation of the left hip ensures adequate placental perfusion.",C:"Given the safety of ECT, external fetal monitoring following ECT is not necessary.",D:"ECT response rates for pregnant women with depression and schizophrenia are not as high as those for nonpregnant women.",E:"Propofol and methohexital sodium, the most frequently used anesthetic agents for ECT, are both short acting and have not been associated with teratogenicity."},correct_answer:"E",explanation:""},{number:7,question:"Which of the following statements about the use of psychotropic medications during breast-feeding is true?",options:{A:"Because of limited data about the safety of psychotropic medication use during breast feeding, nursing mothers should never use psychotropic medications.",B:"The amount of exposure via breast milk is invariably greater than that through the maternal-fetal circulation in pregnancy.",C:"Not all psychiatric medications are excreted into breast milk.",D:"Term infants generally have immature P450 enzymes and therefore may be at greater risk for side effects or toxicity when exposed to medications via breast milk.",E:"It is important to monitor appetite and weight in breast-feeding women on psychiatric medications to ensure maternal well-being and to optimize nutritional quality of breast milk."},correct_answer:"E",explanation:""},{number:8,question:"Which of the following statements about management of psychotropic medications in a breast-feeding patient is true?",options:{A:"The infant's baseline behavior and sleep and feeding patterns should be assessed before the nursing mother uses medication.",B:"Exposure to drugs through breast milk carries no greater risk for a neonate than it does for an older infant.",C:"Long-acting medications are preferable to short-acting medications.",D:"Dosages should be increased when prescribing psychotropic medication to a breast-feeding mother.",E:"Supplementation of breast milk with formula will not reduce the infant's exposure to the drug."},correct_answer:"A",explanation:""},{number:9,question:"Which of the following is not a potential perinatal effect of antipsychotic medications?",options:{A:"Behavioral irritability.",B:"Impaired feeding.",C:"Tremor.",D:"Hyporeflexia.",E:"Jaundice."},correct_answer:"D",explanation:""},{number:10,question:"Which of the following benzodiazepines is the best option for the treatment of anxiety during pregnancy?",options:{A:"Alprazolam.",B:"Diazepam.",C:"Clonazepam.",D:"Lorazepam.",E:"Midazolam."},correct_answer:"D",explanation:""},{number:11,question:"Lithium is contraindicated in breast-feeding women because of the potential for which of the following adverse effects in exposed infants?",options:{A:"Cyanosis.",B:"Increased muscle tone.",C:"Transient seizure-like activity.",D:"Infant hepatotoxicity.",E:"None of the above; lithium has no adverse effects in breast feeding."},correct_answer:"C",explanation:""},{number:12,question:"Which of the following is not a risk factor for depressive symptoms during the menopausal transition?",options:{A:"Sleep difficulties.",B:"Chronic health problems.",C:"High educational level.",D:"Prominent vasomotor symptoms.",E:"History of premenstrual depression."},correct_answer:"C",explanation:""},{number:13,question:"In a recent review of randomized, placebo-controlled trials of menopausal hormone therapy, women taking either estrogen plus progesterone or estrogen alone showed which of the following benefits?",options:{A:"Fewer blood clots.",B:"Fewer strokes.",C:"Fewer fractures.",D:"Less urinary incontinence.",E:"Less gallbladder disease."},correct_answer:"C",explanation:""},{number:14,question:"Which of the following medical complications is seen in both anorexia nervosa and bulimia nervosa?",options:{A:"Hypertension.",B:"Hyperkalemia.",C:"Parotid and submandibular gland atrophy.",D:"Esophageal prolapse.",E:"Electrocardiographic abnormalities."},correct_answer:"E",explanation:""},{number:15,question:"Which of the following statements about postpartum depression is true?",options:{A:"Postpartum depression occurs at a rate of 5%â€“6%, less than found in the general female population.",B:"The time of heightened risk for developing a mood disorder is at the end of the first year.",C:"Elevated mid-pregnancy levels of placental corticotropin-releasing hormone have been implicated in postpartum depression.",D:"Thyroid dysfunction during pregnancy or following delivery has no impact on the risk of postpartum depression.",E:"Neuroreceptor upregulation following delivery may contribute to the onset of postpartum depression."},correct_answer:"C",explanation:""}];export{e as default};
